SRIKUMAR ANAND

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

ABOUT ME CONTACT

Machine Learning Engineer with experience in NLP, Timeseries Forecasting, Yolov5 Object detection, etc. Always excited to implement machine learning solutions. Good at programming. Hands-on experience in AWS compute services, lambda, EB, EC2 etc. Good at data science libraries like pandas, NumPy, PySpark, etc.

Phone: +91-9573223190

Email: anand.srikumar007@gmail.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/anand-

srikumar-81a498109/

Portfolio: https://anand-sri-portfolio.herokuapp.com/

EDUCATION DETAILS

- Pursued B. Tech (CSE) from CMRIT of (JNTU Hyderabad) with 69% (2013-2017).
- Pursued Intermediate from SriChaitanya Junior College with 85%(2011-2013).
- Pursued SSC from Gowtham model school with 84% (2011)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

July 2018 - Present

Software Engineer

TechMahindra, Banglore

- Developed an NLP model which can predict the correct Assignment Group and Business service of a given incident/task in Servicenow.
- Performed Data analysis and various hypothesis tests on the energy load curve dataset, and provide data insights to the client.
- Developed a Timeseries forecasting model using LSTM architecture that can forecast co2 emissions in the next 14 days.
- **Created** Streamlit GUI to visualize the time-series forecasting prediction.
- Developed a web application with Flask framework that uses AWS Compute services like **Translate, Transcribe, and Polly** to translate speech and text from one language to another. Also used **Mapbox** API to display maps and navigations.
- Developed Object Detection with bounding boxes model using YOLOV5. Used Custom dataset for YOLOV5.

- **Deployed YOLOV5** trained model to **Sagemaker** endpoint. Wrote Lambda function to detect bounding boxes of an Image and return the result as JSON Object. Streamed the video using **Kinesis Video Streaming.**
- **Helped** in converting DB queries to new Database Schema.

Nov 2017 - July 2018

Automation Test Engineer

Pervacio, Hyderabad

- Created **POM scripts** that follow the user stories and perform various tests
- Developed **POM Framework.**
- Worked on regression and functional testing. Generated results with ITestListeners.
- Used Data-driven approach.
- Performed load testing with jmeter.
- Used various technologies like robotframework, Appium, adb to perform testing. Wrote the testing framework using python and selenium for a different project.

SKILLS SUMMARY

Programming Languages	Java, Python , JavaScript
Machine Learning	Regression, Classification, NLP , Timeseries Forecasting, Clustering
Cloud	AWS
Data Analysis libraries	Pandas, Numpy, PySpark
Database	SQL
Data Visualization	Matplotlib, Streamlit, seaborn
Frontend	HTML, CSS, JS, React-JS
Backend	Django , Flask
Deep Learning	Keras, Tensorflow
Computer Vision	YOLOV5
Automation Testing	Selenium, TestNG, pyunit, pytest
Problem Solving	Data structures and algorithms